<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>startup | Jin Jeon</title>
    <link>https://jinjeon.me/tags/startup/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jinjeon.me/tags/startup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>startup</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Jin Jeon</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jinjeon.me/img/icon.png</url>
      <title>startup</title>
      <link>https://jinjeon.me/tags/startup/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Cancer (NDA)</title>
      <link>https://jinjeon.me/project/navigating-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jinjeon.me/project/navigating-cancer/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In summer 2020, I had a chance to work with the health tracker team at Navigating Cancer, a company that is devoted to enhancing the patient relationship management for cancer patients. During the weird time of COVID, the research team was working remotely as an international team with each of us in different time zones. I was also flying around being in the US and in my hometown Korea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-design-process&#34;&gt;The Design Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used design thinking framework to help us guide our research focus by better framing the problem and solving the users’ underlying needs.We adapted the double-diamond model, which maps the divergent and convergent stages of the design process. The model is divided into 4 phases (discover, define, develop, and deliver). We begin by exploring the users’ problem space through various research. Then we narrow down to defining the user needs. At the developing phase, we would build prototypes and deliver to the end users to test the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jinjeon.me/pdf/navigating-cancer-resources/double-diamond.pdf&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the ideal model is a perfectly-shaped two diamonds, the reality of our journey was rather a deformed diamond process. As we had to go back-and-forth within each phase, we had multiple pivots, which ended up being a valuable process as we gained greater insights to the problem space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jinjeon.me/pdf/navigating-cancer-resources/deformed-diamond.pdf&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homy, Private Social Network for Families</title>
      <link>https://jinjeon.me/project/homy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jinjeon.me/project/homy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In Fall 2015, I took a semester off to build my own mobile app. I wanted to develop a niche-specific social media that is just for families. Starting the project with mere passion and lacking practical knowledge, I self-taught how to conduct &lt;a href=&#34;https://jinjeon.me/pdf/Homy_A1.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;_&gt;market research&lt;/a&gt;, design and build prototypes. I hired a developer to make tangible results, and won first place in &lt;a href=&#34;http://rehoboth.co.kr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;_&gt;Rehoboth&lt;/a&gt; Business Idea Competition with $5k support. I also received free office space from the state government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt; Developed storyboard and high fidelity prototype through iterations of market research, surveys, and user testing
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jinjeon.me/img/homyui.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
From ideation and product management to recruiting, engaged in every aspect of early stage startup as founder
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-homy&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Homy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem Statement:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We are spending the least time with the most important people in our lives, family, while spending more and more time with strangers, coworkers and friends. The cause of the problem has been generally identified as increased work and commute time, and hectic individual routines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Solution:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Homy attempts to solve this growing social problem by recreating online home and allowing families to seamlessly connect. With unique post-it style fridge page, Homy wants to encourage families to communicate more often. The mission is &lt;em&gt;to provide emotional communication service to enrich family’s real, offline relationship.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jinjeon.me/pdf/Homy_A2-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jinjeon.me/pdf/Homy_A2-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jinjeon.me/pdf/Homy_A2-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jinjeon.me/pdf/Homy_A2-4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jinjeon.me/pdf/Homy_A2-5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check more at:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jinjeon.me/pdf/Homy_A1.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;_&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Defining Market Opportunity.pdf&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
